Ignacio Mariano Sticco

Lic. en Ciencias Físicas



Contact info

Phone:

+54 (9) 11-6045-0304

Email:

ignaciosticco@gmail.com

Nationality:

Argentina

Personal web page (extended CV):

https://ignaciosticco.github.io/

Languages

Spanish (native) English (B2 level)

Knowledge

Python (Pandas, Numpy, Scipy), Matlab, C++, LAMMPS, Linux, Git, Latex

Skills

Data analysis Programming Research

Interests

Machine learning Artificial Intelligence Data Science Swimming

About me

I hold a Bachelor's degree in Physics, and I am currently a part-time university professor while completing my Ph.D. in Physical Sciences at the University of Buenos Aires. The goal of my Ph.D. is to optimize a mathematical model for emergency evacuations and propose solutions for these evacuations. Throughout my academic career, I have gained extensive knowledge in predictive models, statistics, programming, artificial intelligence, and data science. I am interested in leveraging this expertise to apply Machine Learning to solve high-impact problems.

Education

Ph.d. in Physics Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales (UBA), 2018 -2023 (about to finish)

Licenciatura in Physics, *Facultad de Ciencias Exactas y Naturales (UBA)*, 2010 -2016. **Promedio académico: 8,31**

Secondary school, Colegio Esclavas del Sagrado Corazón de Jesús

Work experience

Professor in UADE (university level) - 2021- Present

Doctoral Fellow (Conicet) - 2018- Present

Data Scientist in Futbol Sites Network – 2018

I used tools such as: Python, SQL, Google Analytics, Datorama y Excel.

Professor in FCEN, UBA (university level) - 2017 – 2018

Peer-reviewed journal articles

- Faster and safer evacuations induced by closed vestibules
- Evacuaciones de emergencia con presencia de grupos sociales
- Improving competitive evacuations with a vestibule structure designed from panel-like obstacles in the framework of the Social Force Model
- Microscopic dynamics of escaping groups through an exit and a corridor
- Social force model parameter testing and optimization using a high stress real-life situation
- Effects of the body force on the pedestrian and the evacuation dynamics
- A re-examination of the role of friction in the original Social Force Model
- Beyond the faster-is-slower effect
- Room evacuation through two contiguous exits

Courses

7th Workshop on Collaborative Scientific Software Development, ICTP Trieste (Italia), 2019

Machine Learning, Stanford University (Coursera), 2018

Learning how to learn, UC San Diego (Coursera), 2015

First Certificate in English (B2), Cambridge, 2009